<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: news | Sobiwi Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://sobiwi.peterwongpp.com/blog/categories/news/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://sobiwi.peterwongpp.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-02-06T21:47:27+08:00</updated>
  <id>http://sobiwi.peterwongpp.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Sobiwi]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Refactor is Important]]></title>
    <link href="http://sobiwi.peterwongpp.com/blog/refactor-is-important/"/>
    <updated>2012-02-05T19:39:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://sobiwi.peterwongpp.com/blog/refactor-is-important</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This week a lot of refactorings have been done:</p>

<ul>
<li>form builder</li>
<li>highlighting notes on verses</li>
<li>layouts and partials</li>
</ul>


<!-- more -->


<h2>Form Builder</h2>

<p>As you may already known, Sobiwi is based on <a href="http://twitter.github.com/bootstrap">Bootstrap</a> framework. Bootstrap is releasing its 2.0 version currently. But we are still using the 1.4 version.</p>

<p>To make it worse, our forms are generated by dirty (non-reusable) code. There are currently 6 forms (registration, login / logout, forget password, reset password, user updating and church updating). And it is obvious that there would be more and more forms. In the future, if we decide to upgrade to Bootstrap 2.0, it would be a nightmare to modify every forms (it seems that the some css class names have been updated).</p>

<p>Now we do not have too many forms and the refactoring is worth doing. Now we have a <code>BootstrapFormBuilder</code> to use very clean and direct syntax to generate the form structure of Bootstrap 1.4 forms. More form builders could be implemented easily to match the new form structures such as the Inline and Horizontal forms.</p>

<h2>Highlighting Notes on Verses</h2>

<p>The wiki part (user-contributing content) is always the most difficult one. We planned to let the user highlight a portion of text with or across verse(s).</p>

<p>We have developed a jQuery plugin for our own use to highlight texts. That plugin's code is ugly yet functional. Now we need to show the notes on the verses.</p>

<p>For example, there were several annotations (an annotation is note on a portion of verse). We need those annotations being shown as soon as the page is shown.</p>

<p>By the trail we did, it turned out the the current HTML markups are not flexible enough to handle that efficiently. What's more it is confusing to use only one color to highlight the notes.</p>

<p>As a result, we need to re-structure the markups and thus update the plugin we mentioned before (this reveals a smell of code...).</p>

<p>Luckily, the refactor has been done and we now can continuse to implement the highlighting existing annotations functionality.</p>

<h2>Layouts and Partials</h2>

<p>Actually this part is still in progress and I suppose it would be done next week.</p>

<p>The layouts and partials are drawn on paper and made clear what's their responsibily. Now they are clearer and view tests could be written.</p>

<p>It is in progress and we have updated some parts such as the different timelines (in a single verse, a user's profile, user's home, etc).</p>

<p>However, the Bootstrap 2.0 made me stop and think again should it be done now, or should it be done together with upgrading to Bootstrap 2.0.</p>

<p>If any of you have ideas for me, please tell me either though the contact us form, emails or twitter!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[user timeline]]></title>
    <link href="http://sobiwi.peterwongpp.com/blog/user-timeline/"/>
    <updated>2012-01-30T14:00:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://sobiwi.peterwongpp.com/blog/user-timeline</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="right" src="/images/posts/user_timeline_demo.png" width="450" title="User Timeline Demo" alt="User Timeline Demo"></p>

<p>We are now implementing the Timeline - a time-ordered series of notes written by the user himself and the friends he is following.</p>

<p>The screen shot on the right hand side is an actual display from my testing account, which means the code is on the server and is running.</p>

<p>However, the functionality of adding notes is not yet ready for public. We must try our best to deploy it ASAP!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
